I had Dad, Mom, and Pervy Sage.
（ナルト）俺には　父ちゃんがいた。
母ちゃんがいた。
エロ仙人がいた。
ガキは　英雄に憧れるもんだ。
Kids love looking up to their hero.
だから　俺は
迷わねえで突っ走れる。
That's why I can keep running
forward without hesitation.
俺は　どの先代をも超える
火影になる！
I will become the greatest Hokage
of them all!
That's my dream!
それが　俺の夢だ！
はっ！
やっぱ　その面　割るほうが先か！
I guess cracking that mask of yours
will have to come first.
（マダラ）魔像には触れさせん！
You will not touch the statue!
The Secret of
the Transportation Technique
（カカシ）ナルト！
やつの能力は　わかってるね！
Naruto! You know about
his abilities, right?
吸い込もうとする瞬間が　チャンスだ。
Your window of opportunity
is the instant
he tries to suck you inside himself.
そのとき
やつ自身　実体化する。
That's when he's solid.
ただ単に攻撃しても
すべて　すり抜けるよ。
If you attack him normally,
you'll just pass right through him.
（ガイ）カウンターを狙う感じだな。
So it's like you're aiming
for a counterattack.
陽動攻撃が基本！
接近戦の手数で　隙を作る！
Diversionary tactics are a must.
Create an opening through
continuous close combat!
あまり　大技は使うな！
Avoid using big moves!
わかってるってばよ！
だから　分身したんだ！
I know!
That's why I made a clone!
ビーさん！
俺を高く持ち上げてください！
Bee! Please raise me up high!
《もういける！》
I'm good to go.
《直接　触れる攻撃は
避けたほうがいいな》
We should avoid attacks
that touch him directly.
（ビー）ほらよ～！
Up you go!
《超ミニ尾獣玉！》
Super Mini Tailed Beast Bomb!
《万華鏡写輪眼！》
Mangekyo Sharingan!
《双襲牙！》
Twin Fangs!
《こっち！》
This one!
《では　ないな　やはり…》
I guess not.
Then it must be…
《ナイスタイミング！》
Nice timing!
ウォチャ～！！
まずは…。
I'll deal with you…
先にお前を…。
first!
《かっけ～　ゲキマユ先生！》
That's so cool,
Bushier Brow Sensei!
《よし　これだけ
チャクラを練り込めば　いける！
Okay! I've infused more
than enough chakra!
悪いが…。
Sorry, but…
魔像を狙う！
I'm going for the statue!
神威！
Kamui!
首をえぐり取れば→
If I gouge out its head…
魔像といえども
生きてはいられないでしょ！》
it shouldn't be able to survive,
statue or not!
甘い。
So naïve.
ハァ　ハァ…。
《どういうことだ？　まさか…》
What happened?
Don't tell me…
He vanished?
（ビー）消えた？
ナルト！
Naruto!
《岩が邪魔だ　くそ！》
These boulders are in the way!
Damn it!
ビーさん！
わかってる！
Bee!
I've got it!
飛んでけ！
Fly!
He cut through that boulder
with his Lightning Blade.
《雷切で岩を…　ナイス　カカシ！》
Nice, Kakashi!
《間に合わん！》
I'm not going to make it in time!
ナルト　そのままいけ！
Naruto! Just keep going!
クナイは　俺がなんとかする！
I'll take care of the kunai!
Kamui!
《神威！》
《くそ！》
Damn it!
やっぱ強え！
攻撃すら当たんねえ。
He's really strong.
I can't get my attacks to hit him.
大丈夫か？
ああ。
Are you all right?
Yeah…
しかし　あの攻撃でも
ダメとなると…。
But if even that attack is no good…
どうすりゃいいんだよ。
What can we do?!
うわ！
いきなり何だってばよ！
What's happening all of
a sudden?
Hey, Kakashi…
Did you see that?
おいカカシ　見えたか？
ああ。
え？
– Yeah.
– Huh?
やつの面に　傷が入った。
There's a crack in his mask.
え？　どこ　どこ？
Huh? Where, where?!
ほんとだ　左側んとこ！
You're right… On the left side!
さっきのナルトの攻撃が
スカる前に→
Looks like Naruto's earlier attack
grazed him
少し当たっていたようだな。
before it passed through!
ナイスガッツだ　ナルト！
この調子で攻めるぞ！
Nice going, Naruto!
Let's keep it up just like that!
よ～し！　これなら→
All right! Now I feel like
we have a chance!
なんとかすりゃ
いける気がするってばよ！
いや　ナルトの攻撃が
当たったようには→
To be honest, it didn't look to me
like Naruto's attack landed.
正直　見えなかった。
またお前は…　すぐそういう。
You're doing it again…
You always say things like that!
Are you saying
it was something else?
じゃあ　違うのか？
（ガイ）どういうことなんだ？
What's going on?
《カカシ：あの面の傷跡を見ても
ナルトのパンチによるものではない。
From the looks of it,
that crack isn't from
Naruto's punch.
もっと鋭利なもので斬り込みを
入れたように見てとれる。
It looks like it was cut
with something sharp…
待てよ！》
Wait a minute!
隙あり！
You're wide open!
Don't mock me!
なめるな！
Uchiha Flame Formation!
《うちは火炎陣！》
Hot! Hot! Hot!
アチアチ！
Whoa!
Are you all right,
Octopops and Eight-o?!
大丈夫か！
ビーのおっちゃんに　八っつぁん！
ち　ちっとも！
Do I look all right?
結界までやられたら→
Now that he's erected a barrier,
いよいよ　もう面のやつを
先にやるしかなくなったな。
we have no choice but
to tackle the masked guy first.
ハナから　面狙いだってばよ
コンチクショウ！
That's been my plan since
the beginning, y'know!
Damn it!
Could it be…? No…
That's impossible…
《やはり…　いやそんなはずは。
しかし…。
But…
本来　神威を止められるなんて
聞いたこともない》
I'd never heard that the Kamui
could be stopped!
《もし　あの面の傷が→
But if the crack in his mask
was caused by the kunai
I used my Kamui on…
神威で飛ばした
クナイによるものだとしたら…》
《やつの忍術は…》
That means his ninjutsu is…
考えてばかりいても
しかたないね。
It's no use just thinking about it.
《ありえない仮説だが
可能性がないわけでもない》
It's an implausible theory,
but it's not impossible, either…
（カカシ）ガイ　ナルト　ビーさん。
（３人）ん？
Guy, Naruto, Bee…
– Yeah?
– Hmm?
少し試したいことがある。
協力してくれ。
There's something I want to test.
Help me out.
いくよ！
おう！
Let's do it!
Okay!
ようっ！
Yo!
ハイヤ～！　アチョ～！
たいした破壊力だ。
Impressive destructive power.
どうだ！
吸い込む隙もないだろう！
How's that?!
You don't have any time
to suck me in, do you?!
写輪眼をナメすぎだ。
もう　動きは読める。
You underestimate
the Sharingan too much.
I can read your movements.
こいつは　いただいておく。
I'll keep these.
《吸い込む間は　実体化する。
今だ！》
He materializes while
he absorbs things.
Now!
《螺旋丸！！》
Rasengan!
無駄だ。　まだ　わからないのか。
Don't you understand
that it's futile?
カカシ先生の言うとおりだ。
It's just like you said, Kakashi Sensei!
I don't really understand why,
よく　わかんねえけど
やっと　攻撃が当たったってばよ！
but I finally landed
an attack on him!
そうか…。
I see… Naruto didn't undo
his Rasengan…
ナルトが
螺旋丸を消したのではなく…。
カカシ…　貴様が螺旋丸を
神威で飛ばしたのか。
Kakashi… You used the Kamui
to send the Rasengan away.
思ったとおりだ…。
I knew it…
すり抜ける術と
物を出し入れする→
I thought he had
two different jutsu,
one that lets him slip
through things and
２つの術を持っていると思ったが
そうじゃない…。
one to suck things in
or take them out.
But that's not the case.
– Huh?
お前の術は　１つだ！
It's all one single jutsu!
あいつの術が　１つ？
ああ。
It's one jutsu?
Yeah.
分析にかけては
お前の右に出るやつはいないな。
Well, no one's better at jutsu analysis
and breakdown than you.
簡単にでも
やつの術の説明を頼む。
Can you explain his jutsu
to us in simpler terms?
術のことを知っておくのと
知らないのでは→
Knowing what it is might change
how we approach the battle.
戦い方も変わる。
術のネタは　本当に簡単だ。
The way his jutsu works
is really simple…
いいか…
あの吸い込んでしまう術同様…。
You see, the jutsu he uses
to absorb things,
すり抜ける術も
同じ時空間忍術だったのさ。
and the one he uses
to slip through objects
is the Transportation Technique.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
How can you tell?
なぜ　お前に
そんなことが　わかる？
ああ。
Well…
順を追って説明する。
Let me explain it
in order.
まず　やつの面についた傷…。
First, the crack in his mask.
あの傷跡は
俺のクナイでついたものだ。
My kunai made that mark.
I'm absolutely certain.
間違いなくな。
そして　右肩のものは　傷跡から→
From the look of the wound
on his right shoulder,
I can tell it was caused from being hit
by Naruto's Rasengan just now.
ついさっきの螺旋丸をくらって
できた傷だと　わかる。
この２つの傷に
共通しているのは→
What these two things have
in common is that
ナルトの体が　やつの体を
すり抜けている最中に重なり→
they both involve areas of his body
that were overlapping
and in contact with Naruto's body
while he was slipping through him.
接触していた部分である
ということだ。
そして　この２つの傷に→
There is another thing that
the two have in common.
もう１つ
共通していることがある…。
それは…。
That is…
俺の神威の術で
時空間へ飛ばしたクナイと→
A kunai and Rasengan
that I transported
螺旋丸によって
できた傷ってことだ。
using my Kamui Jutsu
caused those two things.
ん？
つまり　このことから
やつの時空間忍術は…。
In other words, from this,
I can tell his Transportation
Technique is linked
俺の神威の時空間と
つながっている！
to the same time-space
as my Kamui!
ちょっ…　ちょっと待て！
どういうことだ？
W-Wait a second!
What do you mean?
なぜ　やつの瞳術と
お前の瞳術が　つながっている！？
How come his Visual Jutsu
and yours are linked?!
（ビー）時空間忍術って→
Are all Transportation Techniques…
linked between all users?
みんな　どいつがやっても
つながってるもんなのか？
いや…　そうじゃない。
No… They aren't…
I suspect it's just him and me.
おそらく　やつと俺だけだ。
そんなことよりさ
なんで　俺のパンチじゃなくて→
Never mind that!
Why did your kunai hit
and not my punch?
消したクナイが
当たるんだってばよ！？
そうだ　バカ野郎！
That's right, fool!
Even with shared time-spaces,
時空間が
共通していたとしてもだ…。
it should still be impossible
to hit a guy
だからって　すり抜けるやつに→
that can slip through things,
ya fool.
攻撃を当てんのは無理だろ。
この野郎。
Except that our theory that
he slips through things was wrong.
その　すり抜けるという考えが
間違いだったんだ。
どういうことだってばよ？
What do you mean?
（カカシ）お前の攻撃が
すり抜けているように見えたが→
Although it looks like your attack
slipped right through him,
実は　お前の体と接触した
やつの体の部分が→
in fact, only the part of his body
that would have been
in contact with yours
was transported into time-space.
時空間へ
移動しているだけだったのさ。
つまり　お前のパンチがすり抜けた
やつの左面の部分は→
In other words,
the left side of his mask
that your punch "slipped through"
was simply transported
すり抜けたというよりも
この空間になくなり→
into time-space and
no longer existed on this plane.
時空間に移動し存在していた。
実体としてはな。
At least materially.
それと　ほぼ同じタイミングで→
And then almost simultaneously,
remember I hurled that kunai
into time-space using Kamui?
俺が神威でクナイを
時空間へ飛ばしただろ。
Just as his momentum
carried him forward
（カカシ）お前に手を伸ばし
捕まえようとした勢いで→
when he extended his arm
toward you to grab you…
前に移動した
やつの　ちょうど横。
俺の飛ばしたクナイが
時空間に移動し終わり→
my kunai finished entering time-space
and scored his mask.
面に傷をつけたんだ。
Did the same thing happen
with the Rasengan?
じゃあ　螺旋丸のときも！？
ああ。
Yeah…
So that's what happened.
そういうことか。
（ビー）でも　どうしてやつと
瞳力がつながってる？
But how come both of
your Visual Prowess's are linked?
カカシ。　やつは…。
Kakashi, is he…?
その眼を　どこで手に入れた？
Where did you get that eye?!
どこでか…　フッ。
Where, huh?
あえて言うなら
前回の大戦のときだ。
If anything,
in the last Great War.
神無毘橋の戦い。
The Battle of Kannabi Bridge…
お前が写輪眼の英雄と
呼ばれるようになった→
The same battle where you earned
the nickname "The Sharingan Hero."
あの戦いでだ。
Are you…?
お前は…。
言ったはずだ！
簡単に口を開くなと！
I thought I told you not
to flap your mouth so readily!
口先だけの男に成り下がった
お前の言う言葉には→
You're just all talk now!
Your words are worthless!
何の価値も　意味もない！
後悔しても遅いのだよ。
It's too late for regrets.
Reality just keeps cruelly
moving ahead.
現実は　ただ残酷に
突き進むだけだ。
（マダラ）現実を見てきた　お前には
わかっているはずだ。
You've seen reality,
so you ought to know.
Not one wish ever gets granted
in this world.
この世界で願いなど
何ひとつ叶いやしない。
That's why I'm guiding it to
the dream of Infinite Tsukuyomi.
だからこそ　無限月読という夢へ
導くのだ。
墓の前で→
I'm going to create a world
where it won't be necessary
英雄が哀れに言い訳をする
必要のない世界を→
for a hero to pathetically make excuses
in front of a grave.
創ると言っているのだ。
おい　大丈夫か　カカシ。
Hey, are you all right, Kakashi?!
てめえ！
まだそれ　グチグチ言ってんのか？
You bastard!
Are you still blabbing on
about that?!
I thought I told you too!
こっちも言ったはずだ。
火影の夢は譲れねえ！
I'm not giving up my dream
of becoming Hokage!
こちとら託されてるもんが
いっぱいあんだ！
I've been entrusted with way too much
from way too many!
ナルト！
フッ。
Naruto!
Heh!
（マダラ）フッ　託されているか。
しかし　ナルト→
Entrusted, eh?
What if you were to lose the things
もし自来也や四代目火影が
託したものを→
Jiraiya and the Fourth Hokage
entrusted you with?
お前がないがしろにしたら
やつらは　どう思うだろうな？
I wonder what they would think?
((自来也：その憎しみを→
I'm always thinking that
どうにかしたいとは
思っとるんだが→
I want to do something
about this hatred.
But I'm not sure
how to go about it yet.
どうしたらいいのか
わしにも　まだわからん。
答えが見つからんかったときは→
If I can't find the answer myself,
その答えを
お前に託すとしようかの。
I shall pass the quest
on to you!
お前を弟子にして　よかったわい。
（ミナト）答えは自分で探すんだ。
その答えは　俺にもわからないよ。
お前なら
その答えを見つけられる。
(俺は　お前を信じている))
（マダラ）ナルト…
託されたのに失敗したら→
お前は自分自身を
どう思うだろうな？
（マダラ）問題を先送りにし
希望という言葉でごまかしても→
虚しい現実が待つだけだ。
託した側も託された側も
虚しいだけだ。
((お前に九尾のチャクラを半分残して
封印したのは→
この力を使いこなすと
信じていたからだ。
(俺の息子なら　と))
ナルト　代われ！
んっ？
やつにひと言
言っとくことがある。
（九尾）悪いが…　こいつは→
てめえの言葉には
当てはまらねえ！
九尾か？
（九尾）四代目が託した　わしを→
ナルトは　ダチにしたあげく
力をも使いこなした！
んっ。
（九尾）四代目は
お前を倒す力として→
わしをナルトに封印したのだ！
いけ　ナルト！
てめえは失敗なんかしねえ！
オッス！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１３人の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。